A little pause... and we are back.
Ah, just my luck to have lookout duty on a
day like today.
What I really want is to watch the tuning
exam.
Oh, stop.
The tuning exam takes place twice a year.
You'll have plenty of chances.
Yeah, but this year that kid from the
Uchiha clan is taking part, isn't he?
I just hate to miss seeing that.
Well, my life will be incomplete now.
What's that?
What in the... Notify
Lord Hokage right away!
You're not getting into this village!
Dispatch reinforcements!
Yes, sir!
The operation has begun!
Lord Hokage!
Leave it to me!
Gaara!
Squad 1 above.
Squad 2 below.
Protect the nobles.
You will not interfere!
Finally, it's my time.
We've all been waiting for this.
I was so frustrated hiding in that
disguise.
You're all sweaty, too.
So gross.
Come on, we're all friends here,
right?
Sound Ninja.
Right-o.
Let's go.
We have to back up Lord Hokage.
Beware of traps.
Yes, sir.
Do it.
Right.
Ninja Arts!
Four Flames Formation!
A barrier.
We have to figure it out.
How are we going to pass this without
dying?
But how?
Lord Kazekage.
That's a barrier you need to do.
They outwitted the Anbu Black Ops.
And the Anbu are supposed to be the best.
Why are you here?
Lord Hokage is in danger.
What a nuisance.
An enemy masquerading as Anbu Black Ops.
So he was using genjutsu.
Yes, there's no mistake.
What's going on here?
Stop it, Gaara!
I must kill him.
There's no point in continuing this fight.
That's right.
Don't forget our mission.
Out of my way.
What are you three doing now?
Can't you see the operation's already
underway?
What is going on?
Tell me!
Gaara!
What's wrong?
His wound's worse than I thought.
And his chakra is almost completely
drained away.
You fool!
It's all because you tried to transform
before the signal was given.
So what do we do now?
We need Gaara for this!
Alright.
For now, you two take Gaara and tend to
his wounds.
As soon as his chakra has been restored,
the operation will continue.
You got it.
And you, Sensei?
I'm going to take care of these guys.
Yes.
Right.
And is the host of this party Orochimaru?
Don't know.
And don't care.
Now let's heat things up, huh?
Sasuke.
I'm sorry.
But the tuning exam ends here for you.
You've already achieved tuning level.
You're a Leaf Village shinobi.
So put your training to good use.
In other words, I'm supposed to take down
Gaara, right?
Our match continues?
Just be careful.
It's the real thing now.
Not a match.
What I must do... is the same.
Not so fast!
Aw, you take me down now!
They won't believe us anyway!
Sasuke...
Well well well.
We had intended to capture Sasuke while
Gaara was causing trouble.
But I suppose not everything goes as
planned, does it?
Garo... I see!
So that was the plan.
Then the Hidden Leaf Village... And
Sasuke were your targets, is that correct?
Ha!
Do you really think that the Leaf Village
is so important?
Now, if Gaara returns, I'll be able to
show you something very interesting.
Very interesting indeed.
But anyway, your stubbornness and incompetence
have allowed me to outmaneuver you.
I've defeated you.
Hmph.
Nothing is decided until the very end.
I taught you that years ago, didn't I?
Orochimaru...
I knew, or at least thought, this day
would eventually arrive.
However...
You're not going to defeat me that easily.
I told you, didn't I?
You should have picked the fifth Hokage
before now.
Because third Hokage...
Right here... Right now,
you are going to die.
Orochimaru... What should we do?
Should we send in reinforcements?
No.
It's risky to act when we don't know the
whole situation.
And if Orochimaru's behind all this,
even more so.
Is Orochimaru... I mean, is he really that
dangerous?
When I was just a child...
I saw him one time, and I... I had one
thought.
That he didn't seem human to me.
That he was just some creature that had
taken on a human form.
It was frightening.
Simply... frightening.
Sir, I have a report!
Giant boas have appeared
near the eastern gate of
the Leaf Village, and with
them a hundred sand ninja!
They've infiltrated
our village, and are
battling our shinobi
who are patrolling there!
Leave behind squads one and two,
and head to the gate!
Right now!
Yes, sir!
This is as far as you're going to get!
We've been careless.
And now even Lord Hokage...
Kakashi, look!
There, inside the barrier!
What is it?
Orochimaru...
Orochimaru!
Why is he here?
Don't tell me he's after Sasuke again!
Hey, Sasuke!
Sasuke!
What?
He's... he's gone!
Sakura, just stay there while I trim the
enemy's numbers down to size.
Sasuke!
Nicely done.
But I'm worried about Lord Hokage.
Leave that to the Anbu Black Ops.
We have enough to handle here.
Besides, Lord Hokage isn't just some
pushover, you know.
Yeah, but... Just remember, guy.
He is the Hokage.
He can handle it.
Are you actually crying because you're so
happy?
Or is it that... inside your heart there
is sorrow?
A feeling of unhappiness you can't shake as
you contemplate killing your old teacher?
I was feeling so sleepy, but now it seems
I'm finally awake.
Yes, that's exactly what I was thinking.
And I was also thinking that you aren't
the kind of person who would hold a grudge.
So it seems that you have neither a goal
nor a motive.
Huh... I guess... well, I guess that I do
kind of have a goal.
Let me see if I can explain it.
I find it very interesting to watch things
in motion.
I get no pleasure when the world is still.
Like a windmill that isn't turning.
I suppose some might find it beautiful,
even if it's immobile.
But to me, such a thing is truly boring.
So now, I want to put things in motion
myself.
The first step is crushing the Leaf
Village.
Hmph.
I see you haven't changed at all.
Sakura.
It was worth teaching you genjutsu during
survival training for the genin exam.
You truly do have a talent for it.
Huh?
Release the genjutsu, and wake Naruto and
Shikamaru.
Naruto will be delighted.
You'll be getting a mission after such a
long time.
What kind of mission?
You'll have to be careful on this one.
It's the first A-rank assignment since the
Land of the Waves.
I feel uneasy about that weird chakra.
But then, shouldn't we wake Ino and Choji
and go in a group?
No time.
I suspect that many sound and sand shinobi
may have already infiltrated this village.
Besides, if you have more than the four
ninja essential to a squad, it takes
longer to get anything done, and becomes
more difficult to hide from the enemy.
You did learn that in academy patrol
training, didn't you?
Of course.
With four squad members, that means you'll
be coming with us, right?
No.
I must not leave this place.
Summoning jutsu!
Pakkun here will track down Sasuke by
scent.
Wait, seriously?
Our fourth member is a puppy?
Alright, listen little girl.
Don't you dare go around saying I'm just
some cute puppy.
But... I didn't even say cute.
Okay, it's time.
Sakura, go release the genjutsu.
Release!
Hey, what's going on, Sakura?
Get down!
I'll fill you in later.
Just stay down.
Shikamaru, you were... this whole time?
You released genjutsu too, you faker!
Why were you pretending to be asleep this
whole time?
I didn't want to get involved.
Just give me a break.
I couldn't care less about Sasuke.
What is all this?
We lied to you!
So fast!
Not just fast, powerful.
Gai-sensei!
Now, I'll explain the mission.
As soon as I do, go through that opening.
First, track down Sasuke and stop him.
Then find a safe location and await
further orders.
Did something happen to Sasuke?
I'll tell you what happened on the way.
Now, let's go!
Whoa!
Why me?
What a drag.
Listen, whiner.
Huh?
Look, if this mission
is a success, as a
reward, I'll let you touch
my paw while my pads.
So there's no reason to sulk.
What?
Come on.
They're really soft.
They're... what?
No one ever wants to shake.
But my paws are so soft and supple!
Forget it.
Let's go.
Are they gonna be okay by themselves?
Yes, they'll be fine.
Pakkun will protect them.
As long as they don't go too far.
This barrier can only be broken from the
inside.
If Lord Hokage would just take out one of
those sound ninja, then we could help.
Put up a barrier on the inside,
too.
Hah!
Hmm.
Doesn't look like I'll be able to get out
of this easily.
Of course it won't be easy.
I know you.
It would be a big bother if someone came
in here and got in your way, wouldn't it?
Hehehehehehe.
Come on.
Something weird is going on.
All the teachers left the students to
study by themselves.
And then there's that smoke.
It's coming from the direction of the
arena.
Huh?
Do you guys see something over there,
too?
I wonder what's going on today.
Yeah, this is definitely weird.
Right in the middle of a lesson and bam!
We're just stuck in here by ourselves.
And we've been in here so long!
Yeah.
Iruka-sensei and the others are late.
Aren't they, Konohamaru?
I know.
I'm gonna play baseball after school.
We've gotten information that several enemy
units have already infiltrated the village.
Then we have no choice.
We should evacuate the students to a safe
place immediately.
Yes.
But we have to do so in a way that doesn't
cause them all to panic.
Right.
Okay, here's what we're all going to do.
Tell them we're having an evacuation
drill.
Did you foresee this?
Dying this way?
Don't think I'll go easy on you just
because you're old and doddering.
I wouldn't want you to.
Now, depending on how good your jutsu is,
I might send you back to the academy.
At least try to make this an interesting
fight.
Jurikens Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Summoning Jutsu!
Reanimation!
First!
A summoning jutsu used as a shield!
And what he summoned is...
Second!
I must stop the third at any cost!
Now's it!
So the third one failed, did it?
Oh well, no matter.
It can't be!
Those people are... What?
They're what?
What are you going to do now,
Sarutobi-sensei?
What can you do?
It's been a very long time, Saru.
Oh, it's you.
You've gotten so old, Sarutobi.
Never in my entire life
did I imagine I would have
to face off against my
brethren in this manner.
Please prepare yourselves.
First Lord Hokage.
Second Lord Hokage.
A summoning jutsu.
It seems that he used the forbidden
reanimation technique.
How insolent.
Then, Sarutobi, tell me.
Does this summoning jutsu mean we're being
forced to battle against you?
Enough with the reminiscing.
It's time that we got started.
Whenever you live, there's always war.
Isn't it great?
Nothing good can ever come of this!
You've disrespected the dead and
manipulated time!
So that's what happened!
I get it.
I guess Sasuke got all impatient.
Oh, man.
Why did you have to pull me into this
anyway?
This whole thing is such a drag.
It can't be helped, okay?
It's Kakashi-sensei's order!
This way!
How long till we catch up?
I don't know.
A long time if they keep moving at this
pace.
Come on!
Come on, you guys!
Hurry it up!
What is it?
Did you see Sasuke?
No.
There are two squads behind us.
That's eight ninja.
Wait.
No, there's one more.
That's nine ninja following us.
What?
Oh, man.
Come on already.
Give me a break here.
They're probably all Chunin or higher.
We'll be wiped out if they catch us.
Wiped out?
Listen, guys!
We don't have much choice.
We're gonna have to ambush them!
An ambush?
That could work.
It would give us an advantage.
Even if there are twice as
many of them as there are of us,
if we can just catch them
off guard... No, it's no good.
I'm afraid that those ninja chasing us are
Orochimaru's henchmen.
My guess is that they're all Junin-level.
I really thought that would work.
But I guess it won't.
Wait, hold on.
Why not?
The level of an opponent doesn't have much
to do with an ambush, does it?
You guys just don't get it.
Let me explain.
Yes.
An ambush is a key battle tactic and can
be very beneficial.
But for it to work, you have to meet two
conditions.
Number one.
The ninja on the run must be completely
quiet and must find the enemy first.
Number two.
They have to be able
to catch the pursuers off
guard at a location that
is important to them.
This is an issue where
they can do a lot of damage
quickly and then conceal
themselves again just as quickly.
And it's only under those two conditions
that an ambush can truly be effective.
Now, the first condition
won't be so hard since
the Ninja Hound's
nose can find our enemy.
And the second one also seems to be in our
favor since we know the geography of our
village like we know the facts of our
hands.
However, our pursuers have studied the
layout of this village.
And I have to assume
that they've been put
through simulated
practices for this mission.
And on top of that, they're probably
masters of the pursuit jutsu.
So they know all the cards we're holding?
Well, I don't really know.
I suppose that an ambush could give us an
advantage.
But so many things are uncertain.
Besides, our enemy is
a special unit that was
specifically put together
just for this operation.
And what are the four of us?
A fool.
A kunoichi with no particular purpose.
A talent.
A mutt.
And me, the shirker who doesn't even want
to be here.
Look, tactics are
about clearly grasping a
tough situation and
formulating the best plan.
And right now, only one plan makes sense.
Just one.
And that is?
A diversion that only looks like it's an
ambush.
So one of us is gonna stay behind and slow
them down.
Of course, the one who acts as a decoy
will probably...
die.
So, who's going to do it?
We need the dog to follow Sasuke.
So that means...
Alright, I guess that I'm... gonna
have to... I'm the only one who can do it.
Shikamaru!
Why does it have to be you?
It's better than all of us being wiped
out, right?
Besides, I'm the only one of us who's got
a chance of pulling off this decoy act.
And of surviving this attack.
I mean, after all, shadow possession jutsu
was invented as a delay tactic.
Anyway, I'll catch up with you later.
Go on, get going.
We're counting on you, Shikamaru!
When did Shikamaru become this dedicated?
His footprints are irregular.
Regular.
Anxiety is probably increasing his
fatigue.
Oops.
Sorry.
I was supposed to be the guy who didn't
want to get involved.
But I guess I'm not quite what you had
expected, am I?
You're right about one thing, I'm tired.
On everything else, you're wrong.
Like our footprints.
This is what I used to make the paw
prints.
Why, he's just a kid.
I can't believe we got caught by this.
So this is the Leaf Shadow Paralysis jutsu
we've heard about, huh?
Yeah, if you want to call it by that old
name.
But I'm afraid you're behind the times.
Now it's called Shadow Possession jutsu.
Old man.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Wait a minute.
Eight?
No, there's one more.
That's nine ninja following us.
Of course.
The ninth one's role is to protect against
an ambush.
That person stays a
distance behind the
others, a reserve, in
case of an enemy attack.
But I know what to do.
This will draw out that ninth ninja and
reveal where he's hiding.
There he is.
Darn man.
The shadow won't reach.
I don't have enough stamina to use my
chakra to make it go that far.
It looks like you're at your limit.
This Shadow Possession jutsu of yours is
going to fail soon.
So prepare yourself.
All I really wanted was to be just an
average shinobi, making an average living.
I'd marry a regular girl who's not super
pretty or super ugly.
Have two kids, a girl and then a boy.
Retire when my daughter got married and my
son became a successful ninja.
And spend the rest of my days just playing
shogi or go.
A nice, carefree, leisurely retirement.
And then I'd die of old age before my
wife.
Yep, that's the life I wanted.
And yet I ended up exerting myself.
I had to go and get myself into this
sticky situation.
Well, as you say, it appears I'm at my
limit.
Hey, come on out.
And when you do, cut off his head.
Well, I finally caught up with you guys.
Asuma!
How did you...
You did well, Shikamaru.
Yeah, but it was way too much work.
Stay here for now, Shikamaru.
You've earned it.
Well, Tamari, what's up?
He's close.
Very close.
I knew it.
What do we do?
Leave everything to me.
Well, that was close.
Whoa, what was that?
Tripwire traps.
They're certainly not making Sasuke's job
easy for him.
Sasuke... do you think he might have
been... Oh, don't worry about Sasuke.
It'd take a lot more than that to get rid
of him.
He'll be fine.
Now then, shall we begin this?
First, let me restore these
dear old companions of
yours to something more
like their former selves.
And then, if you're ready,
Sarutobi-sensei...
What the devil kind of jutsu is that?
A forbidden one.
It's a summoning jutsu called...
Reanimation.
Normally, a summoning jutsu requires the
blood of the one casting it.
But I've heard that this jutsu,
which summons the dead to the world of the
living, demands the
sacrifice of a living
body to be used as a
vessel for the dead soul.
So...
but then the living body is encased in a
shell of dust and earth that takes on the
appearance of the dead spirit's earthly
form.
Those spells he implanted
in their skulls, they sap the
spirits of their will and
transform them into his puppets.
Mere killing machines.
Now they're complete.
You demon.
They look just the same as I remember.
Have you ever felt the joy
and fulfillment of humiliating
and destroying the one
you once called sensei?
No, I suppose not.
Perhaps vicariously through me you'll get
a hint of what I mean.
Just a taste before you die.
Lord Hokage!
Don't be deceived by their appearance!
That is not the first Hokage!
Nor the second!
Whatever they may look like!
I'm aware of that.
Now I know you've been
playing games with me for a
long time, so it's time for
you to play the first game!
All right, let it begin.
Fire style!
Dragonflame bombs!
Alchemy!
Fire style!
Dragonflame bombs!
Pfft!
It's no less than I'd expect from a former
Hokage.
Water style, water shockwave!
Earth style mudwall!
As quick and strong as ever, I see.
Fighting the two of you at once is quite a
challenge.
I can't wait to see
what you can do.
I can't wait to see what you can do.
The hidden jutsu of the first Hokage.
Secret Earth Jutsu.
Deep Forest Creation.
It's over.
Looks to me like this fight is over.
Say, Sensei?
We're all here I see.
Good.
All right then, let's start evacuating the
building.
That's it, no rushing, no panicking.
Konohamaru!
Amaru, is something wrong?
You look like you have a tummy ache.
Mm-mm.
That's not it at all.
Ninja Art!
Summoning Jutsu!
Monkey King Enma!
Hmm.
So a pesky newcomer has arrived.
That old monkey Enma.
It's you again.
I should have known this would happen.
You fool, Sarutobi.
You should have killed him when you had
the chance.
Better late than never.
Heh.
It's too late now.
Quickly!
Enma!
Adamantine!
Nyoi!
Stop him now!
Do not let him transform!
All right, then.
Understood!
Nyah!
Transform!
At last!
Unbelievable.
I never dreamed I would live to see this.
Okage-level combat!
Good for you, old man.
At least you've made this a little more
interesting.
One of it.
One swing of the Grass Longsword!
I'm ready, Enma!
No matter how strong my body is...
The Grass Longsword will still hurt me!
I knew that.
C'mon!
I'll go get you.
I'll make you pay for this!
I'm going to use this thing for a while.
I have to do this!
C'mon Enma!
Y-you'll die, too!
Huh!
I'd rather die, huh?
Quite the opposite.
Okay then.
That was foolish.
Trying to fight the three of us without
using your shadow clone, Jutsu.
Oh, are you all right, Sensei?
Don't tell me you're through already.
You, the great sage who has mastered all
the Jutsu of the Leaf Village,
the legendary professor and warrior...
Oh, I'm so disappointed.
Lord Hokage!
Save your breath.
He can't help you now.
Orochimaru, you're a fool!
It's over.
I'm going to snap you like a twig.
It should have been done years ago.
I think you're about to die.
What?
You're a man who wants to kill!
You're not dead, you're prepared to die.
What did you do to me?
You're a good man.
Come on then.
Orochimaru's will.
So be it.
I have only one weapon left.
The fourth Hokage's jutsu.
First Lord Hokage.
Second Lord Hokage.
Forgive me for using it, but I must.
What is it, sensei?
You look a little out of breath.
Long day.
You poor thing.
All you really want is to take a long,
quiet nap, isn't it?
Why are you laughing?
Should I be weeping?
It's sad to see how
old you've grown, you
who were once hailed
as the supreme shinobi.
What?
What the hell?
What is going on?
Who... or what is that?
What is this?
Who the devil are you?
You have lost it, old man.
Don't you recognize me?
It's me, Orochimaru.
It can't be.
Then you've mastered even that forbidden
jutsu?
It's been ten years of hard work since I
left the village.
You're no longer human.
You're a demon!
Yes, he did it after all.
This is why I could never choose you to be
the fourth Hokage.
Your mind and soul are twisted.
You're no longer human.
So I've finally been found out,
eh?
Oh, such a pity.
Orochimaru!
Explain yourself, what is the meaning of
this?
And after I set all those booby traps to
give me plenty of warning...
I wasn't expecting you.
I should have known you could get past
anything.
A steady flow of people have gone missing
from the village.
Geni, Chunin, even Anbu Black Ops.
Many of them were last seen with you.
And you've been acting rather strangely.
You, a superior shinobi.
How could you have done such a thing?
Now I'll have to kill you as well.
So you admit it.
Then it is all your doing, Orochimaru.
But why?
What exactly are you up to in here?
Oh, well.
Since you've caught me red-handed, there's
no point in pretending now, is there?
It's research.
I'm developing jutsu.
It's forbidden jutsu you're after,
isn't it?
Just what is it you want?
I want to know every jutsu in the world.
And even those jutsu yet to be discovered.
I'm like the one who first took blue and
yellow.
Consciously mixed them together and
created a new color, green.
Only in my case, the color blue represents
chakra.
The color yellow, a hand sign.
And the green, a new jutsu.
And just as there are
countless shades of color in the
world, there must be an
almost limitless number of jutsu.
To find them.
To unlock the truth long hidden from
mortal eyes.
That takes years.
Endless experimentation.
Ultimately, the truth reveals itself only
to one who proves himself worthy.
One who is willing to sacrifice years of
his life.
But alas, I've found there are not enough
years in even the longest life.
This mortal existence is too fleeting.
Yes, even if I were named Hokage, one day I
would die and that would be the end of it.
Orochimaru.
What sort of forbidden jutsu have you been
seeking here?
Oh, I think you've already guessed.
Eternal youth and immortality.
The immortality jutsu.
A technique for eternally recycling one's
spirit on Earth.
In a way, it's a kind of revival jutsu.
You find a body.
A young body.
Pour your spirit into it and make it your
own.
I was using my old familiar form until
now.
Because I wanted our reunion to be a nice
nostalgic one, Sensei.
Growing old is a sad, empty thing.
I only have to look at you to be reminded
of that.
You will die here, old man, while I move
on to another stronger body.
But first, I really must
thank you, and all the
Leaf Village, for preparing
my next body so well.
Now I understand.
It's Sasuke Uchiha!
Exactly.
You guessed it.
It's Sasuke I want.
So you've mastered a jutsu that preserves
your soul forever in the bodies of others.
How many bodies has it been already?
How many faces?
Two or three, perhaps.
But I'll wait for Sasuke until he's
ripened a bit.
And then, when he's been raised
and trained... I'll bring him to my liking.
Tell me, which face would you prefer me to
wear?
Perhaps it would be easier for you to look
on a familiar face as you die,
cursing your brief wasted life.
You monster!
Lord Hokage!
You really shouldn't lower your guard,
sensei.
That's your problem.
You've always been naive.
What's wrong with you?
This isn't like you.
I'm sorry.
What are you planning to do?
Kill me, sensei?
Ninja Arch summoning jutsu!
But can you go through with it,
I wonder?
Sarutobi sensei?
Hm?
Kill him, Sarutobi!
Now is your chance!
Sarutobi... why?
I couldn't do it.
Now I'll correct my mistake and bury you
once and for all!
It's time to end this!
Hm... I'm afraid it's too late now!
Shadow clone jutsu!
No... shadow clones?
He's going to exhaust what little chakra
he has left!
You'll only shorten your life,
sensei.
I think your impatience is getting the
better of you.
Could it be... is he...
Mie Hitsuchi U Ino Ne Toriuma Mi!
Yes... that sequence of hand signs... I
knew it!
So... it's just as the poor Hokage said.
This is the Reaper, the
face of death, invisible
to all, but the one
who casts the jutsu!
Whatever you're planning, it's too late.
It's over, I've won.
The Leaf Village will fall.
You're forgetting that the Leaf Village is
my home.
And as Hokage, I am entrusted with my
home's protection.
I am head of the household, the central
pillar.
He who would destroy my home must first
destroy me.
And I warn you, it will not be easy!
Yen Jutsu!
Infinite Darkness Jutsu!
What nonsense.
In the grand scheme of time,
you're just a trivial footnote in
the brief history of a cluster
of huts called the Leaf Village.
In the grand scheme of time,
you're just a trivial footnote in
the brief history of a cluster
of huts called the Leaf Village.
In time, the Hokage's stone faces will
crumble and be worn down to nothing.
You've never understood that it's far more
than a mere cluster of huts.
It is a place where every year, shinobi
are born, raised, growled, fight, and die.
To protect their home.
These people are precious to me.
We share a home.
We share a life.
And though we may not share ties of
blood...
They are precious to me.
They are my family.
They are my friends.
The pillar of your village.
A pillar full of termites and rot.
I don't have to knock you down.
You're already falling.
And if I do fall, you still will fail.
I am only one of a long line.
I carry this title in trust.
For those Hokage who came before and those
who will come after.
I am the third Hokage.
You can't stop it by destroying me.
A new and stronger Hokage will take my
place.
Becoming the pillar, roof, and walls that
defend the village.
Now Orochimaru.
Get ready.
For I'm about to perform a jutsu that even
you haven't seen before.
Behold.
Sealing jutsu.
Reaper Death Seal.
I've got to hurry.
This darkness is dangerous.
Well.
Must I make you show it to me?
Huh?
Are you going to show me this jutsu or
not?
Hurry.
Let's go.
Finally it's done and not a minute too
soon.
Aw, what's wrong?
You're reeling from fatigue already.
Now all that's left is to catch hold of
him.
I have you.
I won't let go!
I summon thee!
The
darkness vanished.
What is this, Jutsu?
Forgive us, Sarutobi.
We made your life difficult.
And forgive me, First Lord Hokage,
Second Lord Hokage.
Now, seal!
You sacrificed your people.
You were meant to guide them, not toy with
them as if they were dolls.
Are you finished, Sensei?
Have we had enough of this nonsense yet?
Enma, come!
I'm... I'm... got him!
I'm... got him!
Striking Shadow Snake!
Damn you!
Now to finish it!
What is this I feel?
This is bad!
Now die!
Aren't you going to use the power?
This isn't over!
I'm...
I'm... I'm...
I'm... I'm... Fuck!
I... Oh, man.
It's over!
You'll dodge it!
There was no need to dodge the blade.
My fate is sealed.
It is a jutsu of the great hero who once
saved this village.
Once the seal is complete, I will die.
But I will die knowing that I've taken you
with me!
So then... this is the jutsu that sealed
the nine-tailed fox spirit!
Inch by inch, your soul will be dragged
out of you... and sealed forever!
My body... I can't make it move!
Another moment or two and you'll be able
to see it.
It's nearly halfway out.
You'll be able to bid a last farewell to
your soul... but not to your suffering.
For those souls that are sealed by this
jutsu are doomed to suffer for eternity in
the belly of the reaper, never to rest in
peace.
There, the souls of the sealed and the
sealer are forever intertwined,
bound together by hatred, locked in
ceaseless combat till the end of time.
But I will die.
What is that?
That thing... is the reaper!
You old fool!
Do you really think I'll just stand here
like a frightened child and do nothing?!
You, the old fool... just let him die!
Go along, Sensei!
Hurry up and die!
No...
Hayate... I will avenge your death.
I promise!
That's the signal.
Let's go.
Right.
We have to hold them off somehow.
Where's our backup?
Ninja aren't summoning!
Bring down the house jutsu!
Long time no see, Ibiki.
My, my, what have they been feeding you?
You used to be such a little squirt.
Master Jiraiya.
Jiraiya?
One of the Sanin?
All right, you baby chicks.
Open wide those beady little eyes of
yours.
Watch closely.
When it comes to dealing with strange
otherworldly freaks and monsters,
no one's better than a strange hermit
ninja.
Thank goodness that Jiraiya's here!
Now, unless you want to make this frog
really mad, you'll never bother us again!
So that pain in the neck Orochimaru has
finally started.
Where's Hokage?
The battle arena.
I see.
Don't die on us, old man.
All right now, stay together!
Now everyone keep quiet!
Oh, Komohamaru!
It's not gonna collapse on top of us,
is it?
No way, don't worry, we'll be fine.
Even though this tunnel under the mountain
is really old.
It's strong, too.
They knew how to build things back then.
My grandpa told me that, and my grandpa's
always right.
That's right.
So no worries, we're gonna be just fine.
What are all these other smells?
A bunch of them, all converging on the
same spot.
Smells like we're not
the only ones tracking
Sasuke, there's
something else out there!
Really?
Where?
Who is it?
Friend or foe?
I don't know, but...
But what?
It isn't human.
Tamari, you take Gaara and go on ahead.
Huh?
You're all worn out, look at yourself.
Go on, you'll only get in my way.
Wait a second!
Get moving!
All right.
Okay, Uchiha.
Time you picked on someone your own size.
Whatever you say.
Hold on!
I've got dibs on him first, Sasuke.
What do you want?
She knows.
She knows?
How did you find us?
I planted a beetle on you as you left the
arena.
A female beetle.
She gives off a very
faint scent, nothing you
could detect, but the
male of this species can.
He has a very strong sense of smell and
he'd follow her anywhere.
Anywhere.
Sasuke Uchiha, it's Gaara you're really
after.
That is, because your match against him
was left unfinished.
Well, I have similar unfinished business
with Konkoro.
Because our match never even started.
Well, alright then, if you're sure you're
okay.
Don't worry, give me ten minutes and I'll
come after you to see if you're okay.
Don't waste your time, by then my work
will be done too.
You clueless fools, you don't know what
you're in for.
Imagine, something more monstrous than
your worst nightmare.
Only it's real.
Hmm, I'm having a little trouble picturing
it.
Why don't you go ahead and show me?
Oh, it's not me.
If you're ever unlucky enough to catch up
with Gaara, that's when you'll see it.
But first, of course, you'll have to beat
me.
I am a member of the Hidden Leaf Village's
Aburame Clan.
When we fight, no matter how puny our
opponent is, we don't mock them.
We face them with full strength.
Bring him on.
Tamari, put me down.
You sure you're strong enough,
Gaara?
Gaara!
There's no telling how long Kankuro can
delay Uchiha.
Every second counts.
If we don't keep moving, the whole plan
will fail.
Leave me alone, Tamari.
Go away.
You're nothing but a nuisance.
I don't need you.
I'm sorry.
I don't see the point in continuing
fighting.
Take care of yourself.
I'll be there for you.
Are you all right?
Poison on the blade.
Sasuke Uchiha!
Did he get past Konkuru already?
No, it was too quick.
Someone else must have shown up.
I have no idea what scheme you Sand
Village clowns have got going,
but I'll stop it, no matter what it is!
Besides...
I'm dying to see what you really are.
Gaara, no!
Oh no!
It's happening!
Any second he's going to let that thing
out!
No, not now!
Not now!
No, Gaara!
Remember our mission!
We're so alike, Uchiha.
I don't have friends as you have.
No!
But they're not what makes you strong.
It's your purpose that does it.
In that way, we're alike.
You...
You are my prey!
My prey!
It was tournament.
You're making this too easy.
That did it!
Those damn bugs again!
You made a clone out of bugs, then snuck
up behind me.
Not too bad.
It was simple, really.
I can tell from your jutsu that your
strength is long-range attacks,
not close combat.
Thanks for the dissertation, but I'm just
getting started here.
Don't worry.
If you really want to see
how deadly my ninjutsu
can be, then you're
in for a real treat.
You haven't seen half of what Crow can do.
So far, he's been playing nice!
B-
Listen, everyone.
Everyone, even if the enemy shinobi do
manage to get up here, don't panic.
Just quickly get into the hidden chamber.
Don't worry, your Jonin
and Shunin sensei are here
to protect you, even
if it costs us our lives.
What is it, Konohamaru?
Don't worry.
It's not as bad as it looks.
Our people will drive the enemy away.
Lord Hokage's face is beginning to crack.
That's ominous.
Now, let me feel it.
That eye...
The same eye as before.
Shino... Looks like I may not finish
this before you catch up with me after all.
Shino...
The poison spreading slowly through his
system.
Now to finish it.
What?
More bugs?
He shouldn't even be moving with that
poison in him.
Let me put you out of your misery.
What the?
What's going on?
What the hell's wrong with it?
So that's what he was after.
He wanted me to attack, so he could get
his creepy crawlies to infest Crow's body.
Now they're going after my chakra puppet
strings.
Why?
Right.
I forgot these things eat chakra.
My strings are leading the bugs right to
me.
He severed his chakra strings himself.
What a sucker!
He doesn't know I can re-establish control
over my puppet in the blink of an eye.
It's what makes me an expert puppet
master.
I'm not an expert puppet master.
I've got a lot of experience with puppets.
Like you underestimated me, bug boy.
For the last time, there's enough poison
on that to drop an elephant, so...
you're dead.
These stinking beetles!
They ate through my chocolate strings at
the source!
But how?
I don't get it!
I was sure to cut the strings before they
could find me!
And there's your explanation.
You were so worried about them approaching
from the front...
that you failed to observe the swarm of
beetles coming at you from behind.
All this time, they've been slowly closing
in on you.
Drawn to your headband.
Huh?
To my what?
When I swung at you earlier, I only
pretended to miss.
What I really wanted was to plant a beetle
on your headband.
So then, this bug crawling on my
forehead...
is a female.
Yes.
The poison... it spread through my whole
body.
Looks like... I may not make it after all.
Sasuke Uchiha...
I won't let you get away!
You can't escape, do you hear?
Sasuke Uchiha!
You must remain in
front of them while I do a
This is unreal, his
strength is off the charts!
What's wrong?
Are you not afraid of me?
If this comes down to physical strength,
forget it.
Yes, that's it!
You fear me!
Don't you, Uchiha?
You live in fear every day I'm alive!
Has all your hatred and sense of purpose
dwindled down to this, abject fear?
Is this the existence you live now,
that of a coward?
Come out and fight me.
Show me that I'm wrong.
Prove that your existence is stronger than
mine.
You'll never know unless you fight me.
You'll never feel it!
Attack!
Good.
Now we're gonna have some fun!
Sasuke Uchiha!
With one blow, I'll finish this!
Gaara!
Now it's clear to me exactly why I've been
looking forward to this.
This pain... What a thrill it will
be to crush such an opponent!
Capable of winning!
Defeating me so badly!
Such a victory will make me feel what it
is to be truly alive!
No one has ever wounded Gaara.
And he's done it twice.
He's a freak of nature.
Like Gaara.
But this one's a freak in every fiber of
his body.
For all Gaara's strength, it's only his
right arm that's been transformed.
Ugh...
Yeah...
There's more.
So much more!
What the...
What the hell is this guy?
How many of these things are gonna grow
out of him?
He's even faster!
Only by predicting his moves, do I have
any chance of dodging him.
Without my shotgun, I'd be dead already.
Uh...
You can't use my Chidori!
Fire Style!
Fireball Jutsu!
Even slowing down... this level of Jutsu
is useless!
You're finished!
It's a Chidori or nothing!
I'm not going to let you get away with
this!
So, looks like you're good for two bursts.
That's about your limit.
At this stage of your
chakra development, you've
only got two shots of
Chidori in you per day.
And you weren't using your Sharingan,
which you would be in an actual battle.
Sharingan and Chidori are a potent
combination, but costly.
Using them simultaneously burns up a lot
of chakra.
And fast.
Don't sweat it.
I'm actually very impressed.
Even for me, Chidori's a killer.
If I had to use the Lightning Blade four
times in one day, I'd be running on empty.
What would happen if I tried to use it
more than twice?
Well, for one thing, it wouldn't work.
But remember this.
If you try to force a Jutsu,
not only will it not work,
but the attempt can drain
your chakra to absolute zero.
Worst case scenario, you die.
Even if the worst doesn't happen,
nothing good can come of it.
Trust me.
Especially in your case.
I'm not going to tell you how it works.
Is that it?
That was the best demonstration you could
make of the value of your existence?
That's just pathetic, truly.
Your hatred, it's weak.
You're far too soft and forgiving.
The greater the hunger for revenge,
the greater the hate.
And it's the power of hate that gives you
the strength to kill.
Shut up.
You know what that means, don't you?
Just shut up!
It means you can't win.
You are weaker than I am!
There's a reason Itachi let me live.
The reason he chose me to be the one to
track him down and kill him.
I am an Avenger!
The curse...
The
curse mark again?
I can't... I can't move my body!
I can't move my body!
This... This guy...
S-Sasuke!
What... what are you doing here?
He's losing control again, just like
before!
Sasuke, hold on!
Kakashi-sensei said that bruise was
nothing to worry about!
Hey, uh... Sakura... Earth to Sakura!
What do you want?!
This guy over here!
Who the hell is he?!
His outward appearance may be different.
But he's the one you know as Gaara.
I was born a monster.
So this is what he was talking about!
He did this... to Sasuke!
Hey, little girl.
I guess now would be the time to tell you
I'm not the fighting type.
I can see that by looking at you!
Sasuke!
So... it's you.
You're the one I didn't kill that day.
Guys, get up!
We have to go now!
Die, Sasuke Uchiha!
Move it!
Sakura!
Mommy?
Am I...?
Hey, that's so cool!
Hm?
Ah...
What about... food shapes?
Can you do that?
Uh...
Huh... Huh?
Whoa!
Grilled squid!
Oh...
Ramen!
Uh... cherries!
Lobster!
Uh... sea urchin rice bowl!
How about...
A really big poop.
Can you do that?
Tamari.
Kankuro.
Yes, sir.
Gaara.
Tamari.
Yes?
Hmm...
Hey, Yashimaru.
I don't seem to get sleepy even when it's
nighttime.
Why is that?
Now, that's a problem.
Normally, when you close your eyes,
you should get tired.
Oh, really?
Hey... why... Hm?
Why don't I have a mother?
Oh, uh...
Instead of a mother, you get to have me,
Lord Gaara.
And that... is because I'm going to remain
by your side... always.
Hm...
Oh...
Hm?
Hm...
Oh... is it lunchtime?
Mm-hm.
Yeah!
Good kick!
Come on!
He looks to me!
Quickies open!
Pass it!
Power shot!
Oh, man, now what do we do?
I don't know any wall climbing,
Jutsu.
Do you?
Is... him!
E... Uh...
Here.
It's that Gaara!
Run!
Run, run!
Watch the cảps!
No wait!
Don't run away!
Please.
I don't wanna be alone
anymore... Ahhhhhh...
No, Gaara!
You can't do this!
It doesn't matter what I do.
The sand just gets in the way.
Gaara...
Yashimaru...
As a member of the Medical Corps,
our leader, Lord Kazekage, has asked that
I see to your safety and well-being
personally.
Please, Gaara, it hurts me to see you do
that.
Yashimaru... sorry.
What, this?
Don't worry, it's barely more than a
scratch.
The wound you got...
Does it hurt?
Hm.
Yes, a little bit.
But it'll heal in no time.
Hm...
What does pain feel like?
Hm?
You see, I've never
actually been injured
before, and I was
wondering what it was like.
Hm...
How can I put it, it's very difficult,
or maybe upsetting's what I mean.
Hm...
It's like when someone is struck or cut.
It's a feeling that's very hard to take.
When you're hurt, you don't feel normal.
I'm not explaining it very well.
Basically, it's a situation you want to
avoid if at all possible.
I think I might be hurting too,
just like everyone else.
I know I'm not bleeding, but lately I've
felt a lot of pain here.
Wound your body, and the blood will flow
following fast on the heels of pain.
But as time passes, the pain eventually
fades away.
With the help of medicine, it can heal
even faster.
But even more dangerous
is a wound dealt to the heart,
because there's nothing
that has more trouble healing.
A wound to the heart?
Wounds to the heart are a little different
from wounds to the flesh.
Unlike an injury to the
body, there is no medicine
for a wounded heart, and
sometimes it never heals.
But don't worry.
There is one thing that can mend a broken
heart.
But it's a very complicated remedy.
It can only be administered to you by
another person.
So then, what am I supposed to do?
There's one thing that can heal the heart.
Only one.
What is it?
It's love, Gaara.
Love?
You've got it.
But... but how am I supposed to get rid of
it?
What is it I have to do to get rid of this
pain?
Don't you know, Gaara?
It has already been given to you.
Love is... the heart's desire to serve
someone precious to you.
To watch over them.
To care for them.
Like my sister did for you.
There's no question that my older sister
always loved you.
The sand automatically rushes to protect
you, just like the love of a mother.
I believe your mother's will is carried in
every grain of that sand.
My sister, even after death, wants more
than anything to protect you.
Yashimaru... Huh?
What is it, Gaara?
Thank you for all of your help.
You know, for stopping me before.
You're very welcome.
After all, you're special, Gaara.
I hold you very dear to me.
Can you understand the pain that I feel?
It tastes like iron.
Hey, Yashimaru.
I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
I need some of your medicine.
Sorry about earlier.
I know it must have hurt.
I brought you some medicine.
If you want.
Get out of here!
Freak!
I was right.
No one wants me.
Why?
Why do I have to be such a freak?
What am I?
Only one thing cures a wounded heart,
and that's love, Gaara.
Yashimaru...
I know nothing about love.
No one understands love.
Why, Gaara?
Why me?
Why is it always me?
Why
me?
You did well, Gaara.
You did very well.
Why, Yoshimaru?
Why did you do it?
I don't understand.
You see, I was ordered to kill you,
Gaara, by Lord Kazekage, your father.
My father...
Why me?
Why would... my father...
All these years you have been watched and
studied as part of a great experiment.
It became clear that you
could never control it, the
Shukaku that possesses
the power of the sand itself.
The day is coming when you will be able to
control it.
And your existence will be too dangerous
for the village.
It had to be done before then.
You... you had to obey my father.
You didn't have any choice.
You're wrong.
I had a choice.
Yes, Lord Kazekage made his wishes known
to me.
But... I could have refused if I had
chosen to.
I suppose it's because, deep in my heart,
I hate you, Gaara.
I've always hated you.
My sister died bringing you into this
world.
I can't forgive you for that.
I told myself that you were all that was
left of her.
And since I loved her, I should love you.
I tried, but I never could.
It wasn't her choice to have you... to be
made a human sacrifice.
And so she died, cursing this village.
The day she died, I felt a wound in my
heart that I knew would never heal.
Your name is... the one your mother gave
you.
Your name is Gaara.
A demon that loves only itself.
Love no one else.
Care for no one's existence but your own.
Fight only for yourself.
In that way, you will be sure to survive.
This is the dying gift your mother left
you.
But not out of maternal affection.
It was not from love that she gave you
your name.
It was from her undying rage at this
village.
It was part of her curse.
That you should survive and grow.
Her hate lives on in you.
You were never loved, Gaara.
Never.
This is the end.
There's no question that my older sister
always loved you.
Love?
Yeah!
You're the one I loved...
And this is the end.
But... Nanami...
Rhonda will only love her.
So that's Gaara.
Me.
I understand now.
I'm alone.
I'll no longer care about anyone and love
anyone else.
I'm all alone.
I am all that matters.
Those eyes...
What's the matter?
Weren't you about to make a run for it?
Sasuke...
Naruto...
Who are these two?
Who are they to you?
Who are they to me?
They're my friends is who they are!
You try laying so much as another finger on
the two of them, and I will pulverize you!
What's the matter?
Weren't you gonna pulverize me?
Well, come on then.
Damn it!
This guy!
This isn't gonna be easy as long as he
stays like this.
But I have no choice.
This is gonna use up a heck of a lot of
chakra, but...
It's time to bring in the Chief Toad!
Summoning Jutsu!
What is it?
What do you want, kid?
Well, whatever it is, I hope you brought
along some treats.
Because if you think I'm doing anything
for nothing, you're wrong!
No!
Give me a break!
I'm really starting to hate you stinking
frogs!
Ho, ho, ho!
Anti-amphibian, huh?
Well, take that, you big bigot!
Listen!
I don't have time to play games,
you slimy little squirt!
I can't believe it!
After all my training, this is the best I
can do?
I'll just have to make it work!
I'm the only one who can save them!
Worried about the others?
That's your big mistake!
When I fight, I fight for me and me alone!
Huh?
He's transforming again!
Only by attacking and defeating me can you
free her.
And you should hurry.
With each passing second, the sand will
harden... until it crushes her to death.
Sakura!
He's getting closer and closer to a total
possession.
And if that happens, none of us will
survive.
Sand shuriken!
Wow!
Boy, are you pathetic!
Shut up!
So, uh, who the heck is this freak anyway?
Huh!
Eyes full of loneliness...
I don't know how it happened, but this
guy's been there.
All alone, in that same bottomless pit of
darkness and pain.
He's still there.
That's why he has no one.
He fights only for himself.
What's the matter?
Are you afraid of me?
Or are you still thinking of the best way
to save your friends?
Fool!
Forget them!
Think only of yourself!
Love only yourself!
That is what it means to be the strongest!
What's wrong?
You were so bold and cocky before!
Show me your strength!
Let me grind it into dust before your
eyes!
Attack, you coward!
Fight me or I'll kill the girl right now!
Okay, you asked for it!
Multi-shadow clone jutsu!
Wind style...
Shensong Devastation!
He just blew him away!
Not good!
I think I'll toy with you a while.
I'll watch you abandon your friends and
beg for mercy before you die.
What... what the...
And again!
What's this feeling?
San Shuriken!
What's this... this strange feeling?
Getting stronger!
He... what's he doing?
Flowing through me!
As if I was on fire!
I see it now!
I can't lose!
Weakling!
I have to beat him, even if it kills me!
What is this?
You come at me and that's all you've got?
All that effort... and you couldn't
even touch me... What a joke!
Sakura...
I don't really know how much damage I can
do...
But it doesn't matter!
I just have to give it my best shot!
Shadow clone jutsu!
Here goes!
Get ready for the ultimate secret
taijutsu!
Naruto Zanarki!
Clone body slam!
Okay!
Let's do it!
Shadow clone jutsu!
And another!
Take this!
Leaf Village secret taijutsu!
Straight from the teachings of
Kakashi-sensei!
A thousand years of death!
Boom!
All of that work... and you only scored
one blow?
Put a sock in it!
He attacked at the base of the tail,
where the defense is weakest.
He didn't wound me, but the sand couldn't
absorb the impact.
Have I underestimated him?
Naruto, listen to me.
You have to save Sakura if it's the last
thing you do.
Once you've got her, I want you to take
her and flee as fast as you can.
It's all up to you.
I can... hold him here... a little longer.
I lost everything once.
I don't ever want to have to see that
again.
My trusted comrades falling... right in
front of me.
Your comrades?
Sasuke...
I will not allow my comrades to die.
That is absolute.
I get it now.
Of course.
Going through life with the exact same
sadness and loneliness that I had to carry?
He fought only for himself, never relying
on anyone.
And because of that, I thought that he
possessed strength.
I really did.
Naruto... I don't know.
I guess I should have known better.
That's not what real strength is.
If you never fight for anyone but
yourself, you'll never be strong,
no matter what you do.
The truth is, when a person has something
precious they want to protect...
It's only then... that they become
genuinely strong.
You will get strong.
Very strong.
He's releasing a massive amount of chakra.
How is he... doing it?
No matter what happens...
I swear I'm going to protect you!
Come on, let's go!
The P. Shadow Claw Jutsu!
Gee, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to keep you
waiting so long.
So get ready for an original jutsu
straight from my ninja handbook.
What the... how could he have summoned so
many clones!
You gotta be kidding!
This is amazing!
I don't believe my eyes!
Way to go there, blondie!
You show an awful lot of promise!
How did you do this?
Sasuke, why don't you take it easy for a
while?
You deserve it!
Just leave the rest to Naruto Uzumaki!
What happened to him?
Bye, everyone!
Look out!
Here I go!
Unbelievable!
Is that Naruto?
Let's do this!
Direct from Naruto's Ninja Hammer!
Everywhere!
Shuriken!
My body hasn't recovered yet.
I have to use the sand to defend!
Naruto!
Two Kills!
Uzumaki Barrage!
Naruto's Handbook!
Kid... This time we'll use both
legs for a barrage of 4,000 Kicks!
Where did that strength come from?
There's no way... Not to him!
There's absolutely no way I'm gonna lose
to a guy like him!
What the... What is that?
So... He's finally emerged...
The perfect possession...
So that's it!
The monster... Inside of him!
Naruto!
My... body... I used up all my
Chakra... on all those clones!
Sakura!
This is the end for you...
SANBURU!
Kamari!
Jujutsu!
Sakura!
I swear I'll protect you!
Uzumaki...
You really are good at amusing me...
Naruto... How on
Earth can you do that?
Not you again!
What is this?
Huh?
Well, will you look at that?
Shukaku the Sand Spirit!
What do you say?
Will you fight alongside me today,
Chief Toad?
Take a hike...
Why go out of my way to mess with a guy
like him?
What am I, an idiot?
Why?
Are you kidding me?
You already told me you would make me your
henchman, didn't you?
It's only natural a boss would want to
help out his henchman, isn't it?
Don't you have any sense of duty?
Yeah, sure.
I told you I'd make you my henchman.
But we haven't even sealed the deal over a
couple of weeks.
I'm not even 21 years old yet!
I can't have any alcohol!
Come on, Pops.
Don't be like that.
Why don't you just settle down and hear
the kid out?
Huh?
Pops?
And just what do you think you're doing
here, Gamakichi?
I had nothing else to do.
I just came to hang out.
Huh?
Your father and son?
By the way, Pops, that big ugly lug over
there was picking on me before.
Come again?
Oh yeah, and when he did, our friend here
came to my rescue.
He went head to head and toe to toe with
that monster.
I'm telling you, Pops, there's a heck of a
lot more to this kid than meets the eye.
Is that right?
Okay, kid.
You're hereby accepted as my henchman.
Sit tight.
I'll show you what duty is all about.
Whoa!
Hang on, kitesmoke, right?
Don't you like that?
Whoa!
Awesome!
This guy's no joke.
I barely managed to make that cutty so
heavy.
If I don't end this quick, the landscape's
gonna start changing around here.
Hey, Chief!
Hold on a second!
Don't go over in that direction!
Sakura's still there!
Try and lure him over this way if you can,
okay?
Sakura?
It's his little girlfriend, Pop.
Right, kid?
I have to take him out!
Otherwise, Sakura's as good as dead!
Hm-hm-hm.
Interesting... INTERESTING!
NOT BAD, MARUTOZO-MAKI!
This isn't good!
Kana!
He's really going to do it!
I have to get out of here!
He's done it.
I don't like this at all, Chief Toad.
What's gonna happen?
If he's set the Play Possum Jutsu in
motion, then the Shikaku will be unleashed!
I'm finally free!
Here I come, baby!
Here we go!
I hope you're ready to die!
Let's do this!
I'm gonna jump!
Huh?
Wind style!
Air bullets!
Water style!
Liquid bullets!
Oh, this is nice.
I didn't know it was gonna rain.
What kind of a battle is this turning
into?
Remember, Chief!
Not in that direction!
Will you shut up?
I know already!
Ready!
Air bullets!
Liquid bullets!
Too bad.
This is bad, Chief!
There's one more coming!
Ugh!
I did it!
I killed him!
Now that kind of hurt.
That was an awful lot of chakra that you
blasted me with, I have to admit.
Hit me with a couple more of those,
even I won't last much longer.
Chief, what should we do?
Well, for starters, you can wake up the
spiritualist medium to release that jutsu.
How am I supposed to do that?
Just fire off a few rounds at him!
Liquid bullets!
You missed!
Hey, Chief!
You're gonna have to keep a grip on him if
you want me to get a shot at him!
My body doesn't have any claws or horns to
dig into the enemy with!
Then what the heck are we supposed to do?
Use the transformation jutsu to change
into something that has what we need!
Then again...
I'm not particularly good at
transformations.
Huh?
Don't worry about it!
You shall act upon my will and make a hand
sign!
What?
A combined transformation!
Uh, okay!
Conjure up something with fangs and claws!
Let's see!
Uh... Here we go!
Hey!
Wait a second!
Fangs and claws!
Yeah!
Transform!
That's the...
Okay, kids!
You're on!
Let's do it!
Rise and shine!
How's that?
Good.
Not much time has passed since the meteor
went under.
That one blow should have done the trick!
Aw, that's just great!
Give me a break!
I just got here!
No, it's alright!
Huh?
What's that?
What's that, anyway?
The one on the top!
You... You think
that's my fault?
Uh... Uh...
Well, who do you think you are?
Damn!
How much strength does this guy have left?
This ain't good.
Naruto and I have already used up all of
our chakra.
I'll wipe you from the face of the Earth.
I will not cease to exist!
Ha ha!
Twenty!
Twenty-one!
Kakashi, how many did you take down?
Twenty-two.
Looks like I win another round,
huh buddy?
That last one I knocked off was my
twenty-third.
Yeah, yeah, alright.
I love that two-couple-for-school attitude
of yours.
That's why you're my number one rival.
Hehe.
Let's go.
Alright!
He still has my arms!
Can't use an achu so-Don't you think it's
about time you took a rest, old man?
I won't let this village-Stop.
Are we swallowed up by your ambition?
Nothing can stop my ambition.
You are going to die here.
I don't care if you are Third Hokage.
You're nothing but a withered old fool.
Do you honestly believe you have the
strength needed to stop me now?
Have you even the slightest idea what's
befalling your precious little village?
Do not underestimate the shinobi of this
village.
No!
Not another step!
You are done here!
No!
Sakura!
You have to save Sakura if it's the last
thing you do.
Sakura!
I swear on you!
I'll protect you!
Come on!
I don't need much.
Just give me...
Give me some chakra!
No!
What are you all waiting for?
It's just one man!
The Leaf Village's spirit is strong.
You do well to remember.
My... my body!
I can't move!
Come on, fellas.
You've never heard of the Shadow Paralysis
Jutsu?
Then you're gonna love this next one.
The Leaf Village's Shadow Strangle Jutsu.
Aaaaaah!
Expansion Jutsu!
Gaaaaaah!
What?!
Mind Destruction Jutsu!
Wh... what are you doing?
Stop it!
Stop!
Aaaah!
Mmm...
Reminds you of the good old days,
doesn't it?
You bet it does.
The Inoshika-cho trio is back.
Let's go, Kuramaru!
Right.
Never mind the odds our Leaf Shinobi are
up against.
They'll lay down their lives for this
village.
How little you understand.
Mastering every jutsu will not give you
unsurpassable strength.
The poison in my body
is... Try not to move, Shino.
I've injected my parasites.
They're neutralizing the poison.
Dad...
It was one of my first lessons.
It's not until you've protected someone
precious...
that the true strength of the Shinobi can
emerge!
I am going to protect everyone!
Get ready, you creepy monster!
I've had it with you!
Did... did he win?
A plain old headbutt, huh?
Well, he's not the most elegant fighter
I've ever seen.
But to dredge up the chakra he needed,
worn out as he was...
He might be the biggest knucklehead I've
ever come across.
But I haven't seen a kid with this much
promise in ages.
Wish I could stick around to see how this
ends.
But I've reached my limit, too.
Gamakichi!
It's time we went back!
Okay, Pops.
Let's do it.
That's it.
I can't go any further.
I've used up all my chakra.
And from the look of you, so have you.
You and I are a lot alike.
More than you know.
We shouldn't be doing this.
All right, then.
You and I both know
I haven't the strength
left to rip all of your
soul from its shell.
You and I both know that.
And yet, your ambitions end here and now.
This isn't over!
There isn't any stopping my ambition!
Yours is an obsession.
This need to drown yourself in jutsu.
And for this transgression, you shall be
punished.
I shall take away all the jutsu you hold
so dear.
What did you say?
Impossible!
You wouldn't dare!
The seal is set!
My... my arms!
There you have it.
Your arms are useless to you now.
And without those arms, you will never
form another hand side.
Ninjutsu is forever out of your reach!
You feeble old man!
Give me back my arms!
Your foolishness is unparalleled,
Orochimaru.
My one regret is that I couldn't take you
with me.
Farewell, disciple.
May we meet again in the next world.
You decrepit old man!
How dare you!
How dare you take my jutsu from me!
Where the tree leaves dance, one shall
find flames.
The fire's shadow will illuminate the
village.
And once again, tree leaves shall bud
anew.
Sarutobi!
Let me remove the blade.
A fitting end for one who had mastered the
way of the shinobi.
My arms... feel as if they're on fire!
Lord Orochimaru!
Our mission has failed.
Release the barrier.
Take me back!
Right!
Release!
Stop them!
Ninja heart!
Spider web neck!
Watch out!
A chakra web!
And we flew right into it!
Kakashi!
They're pulling out!
We should go after them!
Wait, guy.
I'm not so sure.
That's right.
Let's not be too hasty.
If we rush in, we might get snared in
their traps.
So... you propose that we do nothing,
eh, Kabuto?
Well, aren't you the clever one.
Time to call it a day.
Are you gonna run away from me again?
That would be too obvious.
Why should I show my hand when it's so
much more fun keeping you in the dark?
That eye of yours can't see everything,
can it?
Unlike the Uchiha clan, you haven't
mastered it yet.
Oh well.
Tamari...
Kankuro!
I'll leave her with you.
What could it be.
.. that makes him so strong?
What are you doing?
I told you not to talk to him!
Let's get out of here!
Watch out!
It's... it's him again!
Why don't you just go away?
Go away, you... you freak!
Freak!
Why don't you die?
He's a monster!
Don't even look at him!
I told you to stay away from him!
Go away!
It's all a distant memory now.
Why do I exist, I used to ask myself.
And then I found out.
But I knew that something else was going
to happen.
Something else had been taken from me.
Something even more important.
And that is when I truly despaired.
My purpose?
In all the world, there was no one who
needed me.
I was... unnecessary.
No!
Stay away!
It's almost unbearable, isn't it?
The feeling of being all alone.
I know that feeling.
I've been there.
In that dark and lonely place.
But now there are others.
Other people who mean a lot to me.
I care more about them than I do myself.
And I won't let anyone hurt them.
That's why I won't ever give up.
I will stop you.
Even if I have to kill you!
But why?
Why would you do this for anyone but
yourself?
Because they saved me from myself.
They rescued me from my loneliness.
They were the first to accept me for who I
am.
They're my friends.
...
Well, love is... the heart's desire to
serve someone who is precious to you.
To watch over them, like my sister did.
For you, Gaara.
Love... is that the thing that makes him
so strong?
Naruto, that's enough.
Look, Sakura's gonna be alright.
The sand crumbled away, she's free.
This guy's chakra is all used up.
That's a relief.
That's enough.
It's over.
But Gaara... I never thought I'd see this.
He's had it.
Alright, Gaara.
Who
knows, Naruto Uzumaki... Perhaps even I,
someday...
Tamari... Konkoro... Hm?
I'm sorry.
Huh?
Don't worry about it.
It's raining.
Even the heavens weep.
We are gathered here to remember and honor
not only the third Hokage, but all those
who sacrificed themselves in this battle
so that our village would survive.
Why did it have to happen?
Why did someone so good have to die?
Why?
Are those for Hayate?
Better make it quick.
The Hokage's funeral has already begun.
And you, Kakashi?
Paying respects to Obito?
Instead of constantly
inventing new excuses for
being late, why don't you
simply come here earlier?
I did.
I've been here since dawn.
This place makes me think of the mistakes
I've made in the past.
And I've made so many of them.
There are two bells.
And since there are only two...
One of us will get tied to the stump.
Huh?
You're pretty quick on the uptake,
Orochimaru.
All right!
I got this one in the bag!
I want you to come at me with the intent
to kill.
Well, Jiraiya, looks like I win our little
wager.
Enjoy your time on the stump.
Ah, just shut up, you flat-chested cunt!
What did you say?
You annoying little perv!
Okay, that's enough.
Enough, Tsunade.
You and Orochimaru head home.
You're unbelievable, you know that?
How can you be a ninja?
You keep falling for the same obvious
traps over and over again.
Yeah, but... You could learn a
few things from Orochimaru.
It's always the same thing with you,
Sensei.
Orochimaru this and Orochimaru that.
The transparency jutsu I use is flawless
when I'm out researching.
Oh, boy.
I'm not even sure I want to know where you
are with transparency.
I haven't been caught peeping yet.
It's true, I swear.
Alright then, if you're so sure of
yourself.
I'll, uh, have to tag along next time.
Wow, Sarutobi-sensei, you're a perv.
Iruka-sensei...
Why do they do it?
Why do people risk their lives for other
people?
Well, when someone passes away,
it's the end.
His past and future, all the dreams he
once had, they disappear along with him.
This is true even if he dies honorably in
battle, as so many have.
As Hayate did.
All the ties that bind him to the living
are severed.
All but one, the most important of all.
People.
Parents, siblings, friends, lovers.
The people who were important to him.
And these people, the
ones left behind, are joined
together in a great circle by
their shared memories of him.
A circle of friendship,
trust, and sacrifice
that grows larger and
stronger as time passes.
It's hard to explain it.
We remain in the circle together.
We have no choice.
It's important to us.
So we do it because we have to.
I get it.
Sort of.
Still, I'm sad he's gone.
Think how sad it would be if he died for
nothing.
But he left us something priceless.
Don't worry.
You'll understand one of these days.
Hey, give me some credit.
That much I'd get.
Bye, Iruka-sensei!
See you later!
All right.
Do you see it, Lord Hokage?
The will of fire is stronger than ever.
The sparks you left
behind have kindled a flame
among the young leaves
of the next generation.
A mighty flame, Lord Hokage.
It will burn brightly.
And it will shine its light upon our
village.
And keep it warm and safe for many years
to come.
And someday, out of that new flame,
will come a new Hokage.
Okay.
슛 채 いい A little pause.
..
and we are back.
A little pause... and we are back.